http://www.understandingprejudice.org/privacy/

UnderstandingPrejudice.org takes your privacy seriously. This page contains a detailed description of UnderstandingPrejudice.org's privacy policy.
Note: Because UnderstandingPrejudice.org is a partner site of Social Psychology Network, any use of UnderstandingPrejudice.org indicates an acceptance of the SPN (socialpsychology.org) User Policy. If you do not wish to accept this policy, please do not view any web pages on either site.
From time to time, UnderstandingPrejudice.org may need to change its privacy statement because of changes in its practices. In such cases, we will use reasonable efforts to publish any changes to this privacy statement.
What information does UnderstandingPrejudice.org gather?
In order to use certain features of the UnderstandingPrejudice.org web site, such as the Baseline Survey and Slide Tour of Prejudice, visitors are asked to provide their email address and other information. The choice of how much personal information you disclose is up to you. It is never mandatory for you to answer any question, although it may limit your ability to use some features of UnderstandingPrejudice.org.
In addition, certain interactive demonstrations on UnderstandingPrejudice.org, such as the Implicit Association Test and the Ambivalent Sexism Inventory, are set up to gather test data and display average scores so that visitors can compare their results with the scores received by other visitors to this site. In some cases these data are shared with the researchers who first developed the measurement instrument in question, but in no instance do these demonstrations ask visitors for their name, email address, or other personal information that might identify them.
Finally, UnderstandingPrejudice.org relies on log analysis, database, and statistical software to collect and analyze information about who has visited the web site and how they have responded to various items and features. This information includes details such as the time of each page view, the country from which pages are being viewed, and the general domain of visitors' IP addresses (e.g., .edu, .com, .org). UnderstandingPrejudice.org uses this information to improve its service.
Does UnderstandingPrejudice.org share your personal information with others?
UnderstandingPrejudice.org has never shared information about individual visitors with a third party, and there are no plans to do so in the future. The information UnderstandingPrejudice.org collects is strictly confidential and is used for in-house purposes only (e.g., to better the web site and help reduce prejudice). The sole exception to this rule is that UnderstandingPrejudice.org reserves the right to disclose your personal information, without your consent, to government or law enforcement officials when prompted to do so by legal authorities.
What is UnderstandingPrejudice.org's commitment to data security?
UnderstandingPrejudice.org will use reasonable efforts to establish secure connections with you and to limit access to databases containing personal information to authorized personnel only. For example, the Baseline Survey and Slide Tour of Prejudice use a password-protected system with a secure (https) server similar to what commercial web sites use for credit card transactions.
Does UnderstandingPrejudice.org use cookies?
No. "Cookies" give users a unique, random ID by storing small text files onto a user's computer hard drive. None of UnderstandingPrejudice.org's features rely on the use of cookies.
Are there online risks when using UnderstandingPrejudice.org?
Whenever you visit a web site or send email, there is a risk that unauthorized third parties (e.g., computer hackers) may capture information from your visit. UnderstandingPrejudice.org cannot prevent or take responsibility for these actions. You should not share any information that you wish to keep private.
How can I contact UnderstandingPrejudice.org if I have further questions or concerns?
If you have any further questions or concerns, please feel free to Contact Us. We will make an effort to respond promptly and resolve any problem brought to our attention.
©2002-2020, S. Plous
